<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Bryan Haggerty, product design leader</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Bryan Haggerty, product design leader</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 21:11:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Proud Enough to Put Your Name on It</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2012/11/proud_enough_to_put_your_name_on_it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 21:11:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2012/11/proud_enough_to_put_your_name_on_it/</guid><description>&lt;p>With small teams, the output, whether it’s an app, web site or any other product, represents the people behind it and the tremendous amount of effort they expended to make it. And it’s common for those people to willingly put their name on it, taking accountability for what’s great and what needs to be improved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As teams scale up, the division of work on a product is distributed amongst many more people in splintered teams. The sense of each individual having a major impact on the end product is reduced. The product takes on a life of its own, without much acknowledgement of the individuals behind it. Whether the end result is a success or failure, it becomes easy to hide amongst the crowd. But no matter how big it gets, people still tend to care when their name is attached to something. Everyone should be proud of the work they’re doing…enough to put their name on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Joining Twitter</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/02/joining_twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/02/joining_twitter/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/twitter-offer.jpg" alt="Twitter Offer" width="600" height="343" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>Almost 3 years ago I posted my first tweet while on a trip to Washington DC.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet tw-align-center" lang="en">
 &lt;p>
 Sitting in a hotel in DC about to look for some delicious Thai food.
 &lt;/p>
 &lt;p>
 &amp;mdash; Bryan Haggerty (@bhaggs) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bhaggs/statuses/10253631">March 21, 2007&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A somewhat inane first tweet, and I’m happy to say that I did actually find that delicious Thai food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twitter’s early simple premise of sharing what you’re doing with friends has evolved to become a communication platform with seemingly boundless potential, which is yet to be fully realized. And that is why I’ve decided to join Twitter as part of their &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/twittermobile">mobile&lt;/a> team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Screenshot Management with LittleSnapper</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/screenshot_management_with_littlesnapper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 17:59:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/screenshot_management_with_littlesnapper/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/little-snapper.jpg" alt="LittleSnapper" width="600" height="369" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/littlesnapper/">LittleSnapper&lt;/a> is another tool I can’t live without. I frequently use it to capture and tag screenshots of my own work and designs from others for inspiration. Screenshot organizer, full web page capture, and non-destructive annotations make it that much superior to Mac OS X’s built-in screenshot feature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Netflix Rentals Seen Through My Current and Former Neighborhoods</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/netflix_rentals_seen_through_my_current_and_former_neighborhoods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/netflix_rentals_seen_through_my_current_and_former_neighborhoods/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/netflix-movies-zip-code.png" alt="" width="600" height="337" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>The New York Times recently took a look at &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2010/01/10/nyregion/20100110-netflix-map.html">Netflix user’s movie queues based on zip code&lt;/a>. An interesting comparison is to see how this data breaks down between the places I’ve lived, Boston, New York City, and San Francisco.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Strong commonalities between the three, but clearly Bostonians are more in it for the comedy and pop films. NYC and SF: You really loved “Rachel Getting Married” that much?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Key Shaped USB Drive</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/key_shaped_usb_drive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 09:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/key_shaped_usb_drive/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.lacie.com/us/products/product.htm?pid=11225">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/lacie-usb-key.jpg" alt="" title="lacie-usb-key" width="600" height="250" class="image-centered" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A USB drive key fob that is shaped like a key. Designed by &lt;a href="http://www.cinqcinqdesigners.com/">5.5 Designers&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="http://www.lacie.com/us/products/product.htm?pid=11225">LaCie&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPhone UI testing with Live View Screencaster</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/iphone_ui_testing_with_live_view_screencaster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 11:54:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/iphone_ui_testing_with_live_view_screencaster/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/live-view-screencaster.jpg" alt="Live View Screencaster" width="600" height="389" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>One of my essential tools while designing user interfaces for the iPhone is &lt;a href="http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/">Live View Screencaster&lt;/a>, which allows me to broadcast in real-time a 480x320 portion of my Mac screen to a wi-fi connected iPhone. This allows for immediate visual verification on the physical device. The app can also pass through touch events allowing for the possibility to create simple prototypes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/aaron">Aaron&lt;/a> turned me on to this app and it’s been at the top of my list of every day tools since.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn for BlackBerry at CES</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/linkedin_for_blackberry_at_ces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 23:43:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/linkedin_for_blackberry_at_ces/</guid><description>&lt;div class="video">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Our man &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/robgetzschman">Rob&lt;/a> shows off our forthcoming LinkedIn for BlackBerry app at CES:2010 in the BlackBerry booth. The mobile team is firing on all cylinders these days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>File Your Taxes via iPhone</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/file_your_taxes_via_iphone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 14:28:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2010/01/file_your_taxes_via_iphone/</guid><description>&lt;div class="video">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.intuit.com">Intuit&lt;/a> will release SnapTax, an iPhone tax filing app, for the upcoming tax season. I just may have to file my taxes this year through my iPhone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn 3.0 for iPhone</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/linkedin_30_for_iphone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 16:58:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/linkedin_30_for_iphone/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/linkedin-v3.0.jpg" alt="LinkedIn 3.0 for iPhone" width="600" height="485" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/linkedin/id288429040?mt=8">LinkedIn 3.0 for iPhone&lt;/a> is now available on the App Store. Great work from my fellow Mobile team members. My primary role on the project was designing the user interface but I also dabbled in the code as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Plug</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/smart_plug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 19:56:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/smart_plug/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/breville-plug.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>A smartly designed plug from &lt;a href="http://breville.com">Breville&lt;/a>. Found on our new &lt;a href="http://www.brevilleusa.com/tea/ikon-electric-kettle-1-7.html">electric kettle&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ScrollMotion Iceberg Reader</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/scrollmotion_iceberg_reader/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 17:30:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/scrollmotion_iceberg_reader/</guid><description>&lt;div class="video">
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Love the page slider UI in &lt;a href="http://www.scrollmotion.com/">ScrollMotion’s&lt;/a> Iceberg Reader.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn iPhone app in New York Times illustrations</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/linkedin_iphone_app_in_new_york_times_illustrations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 10:16:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2009/12/linkedin_iphone_app_in_new_york_times_illustrations/</guid><description>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/nyt-linkedin-illustrations.jpg" width="600" height="316" class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>It’s always a pleasant surprise to find our app icon for the &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/linkedin/id288429040?mt=8">LinkedIn iPhone app&lt;/a> showing up in different places. Recently it has been popping up in illustrations [&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/12/06/technology/06apps.html">1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/12/22/business/22apps.html">2&lt;/a>] for articles in the New York Times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rise of the Switch Control</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/05/rise_of_the_switch_control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 09:49:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/05/rise_of_the_switch_control/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/iphone-switch.gif" alt="" title="iphone-switch" width="94" height="27" class="icon-left" />One of the interesting user interface elements which Apple introduced with the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone&lt;/a> was the &lt;em>switch&lt;/em> control. It has a unique place on the iPhone due to its user’s primary method of interaction–&lt;strong>a blunt index finger&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is not surprising that many of the points of interaction on the iPhone are over sized. Lost, is that precision of a mouse pointer. More importantly, on touch-screens, due to the size of a person’s finger, it can obscure useful information in the interface. For controls such as checkboxes or radio buttons, it can be difficult to determine whether the finger press has resulted in the desired action without having to move the finger away from the screen. As such, the &lt;em>switch&lt;/em> control is a cleverly appropriate control, due to that as the user operates the switch he can see the state of the control, without removing the finger from the screen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dying Maps and Their Successors</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/04/dying_maps_and_their_successors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 17:12:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/04/dying_maps_and_their_successors/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a lover of maps. I have books about maps, my walls have been covered in maps (even a 5ft x 5ft MTA map at one point), and I’ve even &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/reducing_the_new_york_city_subway_map.php">written about maps&lt;/a>. Which makes it not surprising that this past Christmas I received more than one gift which was a map.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In preparation for my move west to San Francisco my mother gave me a &lt;a href="http://www.streetwisemaps.com">Streetwise&lt;/a> waterproof folded map of San Francisco. Something to toss in my bag to always have. Yet, the more I look at the map, or rather don’t look at the map, I realize the &lt;strong>obsolescing of this map form factor&lt;/strong>–and likely a chunk of Streetwise’s and other map makers’ business.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkingIn</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/04/linkingin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 18:14:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/04/linkingin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I left JPMorgan Chase and New York City, to try my hand at a new locale and job. Back when I completed school, I had that cliche decision to make, New York or San Francisco–why not both. After three years in New York, it was time to give San Francisco a go. Seeking to work on more publicly facing internet products, the decision to head for the bay area was easy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interaction 08</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/interaction_08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 16:27:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/interaction_08/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/02/ixda-logo.gif' alt='IxDA Logo' class="icon-left" />Tomorrow kicks off the first day of the &lt;a href="http://ixda.org">IxDA’s&lt;/a> first conference, &lt;a href="http://interaction08.ixda.org">Interaction 08&lt;/a>. The sold out event marks a milestone for the young organization, as an all volunteer organization working solely for the community, they have truly brought together a lot of amazing minds. My hat is off to my friends &lt;a href="http://synapticburn.com">Dave&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://noreally.wordpress.com/">Liya&lt;/a>, Nasir, and the many others who have helped put together not only Interaction 08 but the many other IxDA events throughout the years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Demoing the Experience</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/demoing_the_experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 00:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/demoing_the_experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most common ways to sell a customer on a product is to allow them to engage the user experience themselves–the &lt;em>try before you buy&lt;/em> approach. It’s why electronics stores have rows and rows of TVs, sound proof stereo listening rooms, video game demo stations, and plenty more. Whether the customer makes a purchase or not, he has gotten a taste for that product, which will resonate far more than any product photo or video could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Voting Experience</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/the_voting_experience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/the_voting_experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the chance to take part in the voting process doesn’t come around too frequently. It is why when it does come around, it can sometimes be a difficult process–&lt;em>and I’m not talking about making a decision on which candidate to support&lt;/em>. The topic of voting machine usability is often talked about and even the &lt;a href="http://www.upassoc.org/civiclife/voting/">UPA&lt;/a> has attempted to take on that challenge. But an even greater part of the voting experience exists in how a voting location is structured and presented and how polling volunteers assist voters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help Guide for Opening the Vista Box</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/help_guide_for_opening_the_vista_box/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 12:16:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/02/help_guide_for_opening_the_vista_box/</guid><description>&lt;p>A customer’s first experience with a product is often its packaging. The customer wants to take that package home and tear it open as fast as possible–not read a manual on &lt;a href="http://windowshelp.microsoft.com/Windows/en-US/help/2e680b8d-211e-41c5-a0bf-9ccc6d7e62a21033.mspx">how to open it&lt;/a> as is the case with Microsoft’s Vista box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="figure-centered">
 &lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/02/vista-packaging.jpg' alt='Vista Box Help' />&lt;br />&lt;em>Steps to opening the Microsoft Vista box&lt;/em>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Configure a New Dell in 38 Easy Steps</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/01/configure_a_new_dell_in_38_easy_steps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 12:35:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2008/01/configure_a_new_dell_in_38_easy_steps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Can’t afford that new &lt;a href="http://apple.com/macbookair/">MacBook Air&lt;/a>? In just &lt;strong>38 easy steps&lt;/strong> you can get yourself setup with a new &lt;a href="http://dell.com">Dell&lt;/a> laptop instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dell has forgone attempting to provide the user with a simple ordering process in favor of countless upsells. The extra “components” Dell asks the user to configure range from what Adobe, QuickBooks, and TurboTax software to install to decking out the laptop with a carrying case, external mouse, and printer. While at it, throw in a matching flash drive. Don’t forget warranty, accident insurance, and premium tech support. With all this extra stuff, the user probably won’t be able to install it himself–throw in that in-home install and setup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Location Aware City Alert System</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/location_aware_city_alert_system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 23:56:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/location_aware_city_alert_system/</guid><description>&lt;p class="figure-right" style="width: 250px;">
 &lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/location-map.jpg' alt='Locaiton Map' />&lt;br />&lt;em>Google Maps mobile, displaying location based on cell tower usage&lt;/em>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping people informed with timely, contextually relevant emergency, transportation and other public interest information can prevent people from getting in harm’s way or to plan more accordingly to subway delays, just to list a few. Unfortunately, such information is often posted after the fact or on some obscure website that people need to check to discover if there is an issue. And major news outlets are typically not useful for the more macro information which affects people’s daily lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connecting Bookstore Shelves and Book Lookup Systems</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/connecting_bookstore_shelves_and_book_lookup_systems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 14:38:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/connecting_bookstore_shelves_and_book_lookup_systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are occasions where I visit a traditional book store such as Barnes &amp;amp; Noble, as opposed to simply ordering on Amazon.com–albeit rarely. Visiting a local bookstore does allow for that browsing of printed material more easily than an online store and some people do take joy in lingering around the vast shelves. But when visiting a bookstore in search of a specific item, the process can be somewhat frustrating and like a treasure hunt–almost making you rather wait the three days to get it by mail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Network: Collector’s Edition</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/social_network_collectors_edition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 10:12:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/social_network_collectors_edition/</guid><description>&lt;p>Speaking with a friend recently about the fickleness of users, we inevitably came to the discussion of social networks and how users simply abandon one for the next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recent exodus from &lt;a href="http://myspace.com">MySpace&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="http://facebook.com">Facebook&lt;/a>, based solely on the amount of friend invites for Facebook in my inbox, would probably suggest how MySpace users are tired and bored of what they offer and see that Facebook has something at the least different. But in reality, there is probably more playing into this. Aside from MySpace’s spam issues and &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/byespace.php">poor usability&lt;/a>, user engagement has begun to dwindle. One of MySpace’s greatest points of bringing users back was the friend invite. A friend signs up and they want to connect, hence you come back and probably poke around the site for a bit while you’re at it. Eventually all your friends have signed up and you’ve connected with them all. It’s almost like collecting baseball cards. But once you’ve completed the set, now what?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Subtle User Alerts at the Grocery Store</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/subtle_user_alerts_at_the_grocery_store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 16:34:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/12/subtle_user_alerts_at_the_grocery_store/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alerting users in a non-intrusive but informative way requires a bit of finesse. It is about providing information when it is needed but also not disrupting the work flow. When done right, it’s almost a natural assumed experience–seamless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded of this in an unassuming place, not on a computer but at the grocery store. There are far more interactions at play in grocery stores than is often realized. In particular, in a grocer’s produce section where they seek to provide customers with fresh from the farm vegetables, the produce is kept clean and fresh by misting water on the produce–hopefully when a customer is not picking out vegetables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Little Things In UI Can Go a Long Way</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/little_things_in_ui_can_go_a_long_way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 15:53:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/little_things_in_ui_can_go_a_long_way/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have often felt that a great user experience can be defined by the little things. They’re the elements of an interface which pop up just when you need them and disappear when you don’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A nice example of this, is one I noticed today while using &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/reader">Google’s News Reader&lt;/a> application. There is a subtle feature which by clicking a little arrow, minimizes the navigation pane to allow for more screen space for news content. It’s easy to miss, but it’s really a minor feature I think only a few people will truly take advantage but certainly a useful one to have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reducing the New York City Subway Map</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/reducing_the_new_york_city_subway_map/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 11:38:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/reducing_the_new_york_city_subway_map/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a New Yorker and avid subway fan, each day I admire the New York City subway map, designed by Michael Hertz. It is certainly a great piece of &lt;a href="http://gothamist.com/2007/08/03/michael_hertz_d.php">graphic design&lt;/a> and a cultural icon of the city. Its representation of subway lines and geography is burned into many of our heads. I sought to reduce the map to its simplest form, the contouring lines which depict each subway line’s route. To remove the geographical context in order to expose the grand complexity of this weaving system of people movers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keep To The Right</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/keep_to_the_right/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 15:17:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/keep_to_the_right/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/macbook-magsafe.jpg' alt='MacBook with MagSafe' class="image-right" />I can’t tell if I have a predisposition to sitting with walls to my right, but I seem to consistently find myself in that awkward position of trying to overextend my MacBook’s power cable to connect it the left side of my MacBook. Often the power cable is just too short or gets disconnected due to the &lt;em>MagSafe&lt;/em> connector detaching as I pull it tight in an attempt to compute comfortably.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Still Scratching the Surface</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/still_scratching_the_surface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/still_scratching_the_surface/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier I had discussed the topic of only &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/the_surface_problem.php">solving the surface problem&lt;/a> instead of digging deeper into the real problem. The “Reply to All” solution has now been accompanied with other surface solutions to &amp;lsquo;solve’ more email problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an organization that deals with sensitive information, the leaking of such information even if accidental is a major concern. And one of the possible ways this information can be leaked is via email to external addresses. In an effort to thwart this issue, a design change has been made to the email software (shown below), which requires users to specify whether their email is being sent to internal recipients or internal and external recipients. If the user fails to select that his email is being sent to external recipients, he will not receive any indication that the email was not delivered.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One Way to Keep Subway Users Informed</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/one_way_to_keep_subway_users_informed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 14:55:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/11/one_way_to_keep_subway_users_informed/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a pre-paid 30 day subway &lt;a href="http://www.mta.info/metrocard/">MetroCard&lt;/a>, which means for 30 days I can swipe my MetroCard and never think about it until that 31st day rolls around and the turnstile tells me “insufficient fare”. You hate being that guy holding up the line and hate being behind the guy that that happens to. It slows the entire process down, especially when it’s the morning rush hour and there are only two turnstiles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Surface Problem</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/the_surface_problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 16:24:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/the_surface_problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sweeping the dirt under the rug, putting a new coat of paint on an old car, opting for a diet coke and calling it healthy living are all solutions to surface problems that never truly solve anything. They’re the easy and quick things that we think can actually make a difference. Just like in any other space, in software design we see solutions to surface problems passed off as answers to greater issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Earth</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/earth/</guid><description>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/planet-earth.jpg' alt='Photograph of Planet Earth' class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>Photographs of our planet are so commonplace to many of us that we don’t even really think about it. Imagery of our planet has always existed in my lifetime. It was only recently that I even thought to realize that in my father’s own lifetime, photographs of our planet from space did not exist. The first photograph of Earth from space was taken by the Explorer 6 satellite in 1959. My dad was 8 years old at the time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exiting the Subway and Finding Your Way</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/exiting_the_subway_and_finding_your_way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2007 15:45:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/exiting_the_subway_and_finding_your_way/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.grandcentralpartnership.org/what_we_do/2007_survey.asp" title="See more of the wayfinding signs">&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/subway-exit-street-wayfinder.jpg' alt='Wayfinding signs for streets at subway exits' class="image-right" />&lt;/a> All too often, exiting a subway station and getting your bearings can be a bit disorienting, especially in New York City’s grid. &lt;a href="http://gothamist.com/2007/10/16/step_out_of_the.php">Gothamist.com&lt;/a> reports on a new wayfinding system, developed by New York City’s Department of Transportation and the &lt;a href="http://www.grandcentralpartnership.org/">Grand Central Partnership&lt;/a>, to assist people on finding the right way upon exiting a subway station. It is about to be tested around the MTA’s Grand Central Station subway exits. The sidewalk decals feature a compass image displaying which street is in what direction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m Getting a Little Tired of This</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/im_getting_a_little_tired_of_this/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 17:21:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/im_getting_a_little_tired_of_this/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every music artist samples in some way, that’s no surprise. Typically it’s better to sample from songs that aren’t just a few years old. No one remembers the old stuff, thus it can be called current. When Kanye West sampled Daft Punk’s “Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger” for his song, “Stronger”, it was a stretch as the Daft Punk version only came out 6 years prior and Daft Punk has been on the road with their Alive 2007 tour, greatly featuring their version of the song.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple of My Eye</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/apple_of_my_eye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 15:48:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/10/apple_of_my_eye/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Mac-using freshman in 2000 at Northeastern University’s &lt;a href="http://www.ccis.neu.edu">College of Computer &amp;amp; Information Science&lt;/a>, I was pretty much a joke to everyone–mostly due to my computer, but okay, that could be debated. The all too often question was, “how are you gonna do computer science on a Mac?” Surprisingly, I did just fine, and before I knew it, a lot of people were picking up on the Mac trend. By the time I graduated a lot had changed in the Mac world and surprisingly, I actually knew a &lt;strong>handful&lt;/strong> of other people who owned Macs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking Back at Futurism</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/looking_back_at_futurism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2007 13:40:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/looking_back_at_futurism/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier I had &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/this_years_ux_book_same_as_last_years.php">spoken&lt;/a> about what I had thought about the state of current user experience books and that if I am seeking to find new knowledge I would have to look elsewhere. Oddly enough that elsewhere may be in the past. Which as I write this, seems utterly obvious but I think Alex Wright sums it up nicely in his book &lt;a href="http://alexwright.org/glut/">Glut&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote cite="http://alexwright.org/glut/">
 &lt;p>
 “For all the barrels of ink and billions of pixels spent chronicling the rise of the Internet in recent years, however, surprisingly few writers seem disposed to look in any direction but forward.”
 &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drag, Drop, But Not There</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/drag_drop_but_not_there/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/drag_drop_but_not_there/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dragging and dropping files on a Macintosh has almost always felt limitless–drag a file onto an application in the dock, over a folder, onto a window, and things just work as you’d expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living the dual life that I have–Mac at home, Windows at work–I often run into oddities between the two operating systems. While a long time Mac user I use my Windows computer more frequently so we can rule out the idea that I’m just too used to the Mac.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Year’s UX Book, Same As Last Year’s</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/this_years_ux_book_same_as_last_years/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 16:13:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/this_years_ux_book_same_as_last_years/</guid><description>&lt;p>Often I check out what some of the latest UX books have got to offer, always on the lookout to learn more. Unfortunately, recently I’ve noticed a lot of the same. I picked up Robert Hoekman’s &lt;em>Designing the Obvious&lt;/em> and while well written and containing an abundance of relevant examples, I found that, like many other books on the shelves today, it seemed to be a regurgitation of everyone else’s books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BlackBerry Pearl Bytes</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/blackberry_pearl_bytes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 13:39:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/blackberry_pearl_bytes/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been a BlackBerry Pearl user for only a short while, almost a year. It has its merits but my next phone probably won’t be another BlackBerry. There are more than a few quirks, but one that has always got me is so simple to solve that it seems weird it has been overlooked for so long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Pearl was Research In Motion’s, maker of the BlackBerry, first entrance into the multimedia phone space which includes a camera and audio, video playback–all types of media which require a fair amount of memory. With limited storage, it is not uncommon to want to know how much space you’ve got left on the Pearl’s &lt;strong>64 megabytes&lt;/strong> of internal memory, or &lt;strong>65142784 bytes&lt;/strong> as my BlackBerry prefers to tell me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Lot of Hot Air</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/a_lot_of_hot_air/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 15:06:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/a_lot_of_hot_air/</guid><description>&lt;p>The majority of computer users use a right-handed mouse, even if you’re a left-handed, the industry has pretty much almost forced you to be a right-handed when it comes to a mouse. Which is why I’ve become a bit baffled by a design decision made by Dell in their laptops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laptops are becoming more and more the choice for computing over desktop computers and often people like to hook up a mouse to avoid the usable but straining trackpad. Yet when I hook up a mouse to my Dell laptop I’m greeted by one of the most uncomfortable sensations while attempting to use the laptop, a constant stream of hot air breathing down on my mouse hand from the laptop’s fan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Core77 Hack 2 School Guide Featuring, well, Me</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/the_core77_hack_2_school_guide_featuring_well_me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2007 21:56:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/the_core77_hack_2_school_guide_featuring_well_me/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently acted as a “model” for the &lt;a href="http://www.core77.com/hack2school/classmates.asp">Classmate Designertypes&lt;/a> section in &lt;a href="http://www.core77.com">Core77’s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.core77.com/hack2school/">Hack 2 School Guide&lt;/a>. I play the part of various stereotypical design students at art school. I think I managed to bring out my inner &lt;em>Chosen One&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Dude&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>Space Cadet&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.core77.com/hack2school/classmates.asp">&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/me-core-hack2school.jpg' alt='The Chosen One designer' class="image-centered" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Go Outside and Work, It’s Labor Day</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/go_outside_and_work_its_labor_day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 11:07:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/09/go_outside_and_work_its_labor_day/</guid><description>&lt;p>On today’s semi-mandatory day off in America, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labor_day">Labor Day&lt;/a>, I thought it would be nice to take a look at that nice &lt;a href="http://travel.nytimes.com/2007/08/05/magazine/05wwln-lede-t.html">New York Times graph&lt;/a> comparing the number of mandatory days off in many of the top industrialized countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://travel.nytimes.com/2007/08/05/magazine/05wwln-lede-t.html">&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/mandatory-vacation-country.jpg' alt='Mandatory Vacations Days by Country' class="image-centered" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No surprise here, us Americans seem to think even a little mandatory paid time off is too much. Yes, that’s right even today–the day to honor us hard working Americans is not truly mandatory. So stuff another hot dog down your throat and flip on the TV cause there’s nothing to worry about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Need To Be Mad As Hell</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/you_need_to_be_mad_as_hell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 16:08:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/you_need_to_be_mad_as_hell/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/08/mac-bomb.gif' alt='Mac bomb icon' class="icon-left" />I recently discovered that my co-workers have been secretly keeping a running list of how many usability rants I have a day. I won’t lie, it is a fairly common occurrence and an activity I recommend for anyone in the industry. Often my rants are five minute manifestos on why something is designed poorly and what needs to be changed to rectify the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to push that agenda for designing more usable products you need to be as mad as hell and let it be known–in the politest manner possible. Being irked on a daily basis, as frustrating as that sounds, I find to be paramount in the ideation process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ByeSpace</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/byespace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 13:46:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/byespace/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the early days it was email and today it’s the online profile. It seems these days that if you don’t have a profile on a social network you don’t really exist, at least in regards to the Internet–even my dad has one. I’ve had profiles on too many sites to remember, many of which were before the days when we called them social networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="you-looked-hotter-on-myspace">“You Looked Hotter On MySpace”&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I was a hold out on &lt;a href="http://myspace.com">MySpace&lt;/a>–due to its utterly poor design. As someone in the field of user experience I felt disgusted in myself for not only finally signing up to use it, but to also promote it. Don Norman had stated in his classic book, &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0465067107/donnormanA">The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/a>&lt;/em> that we are to send a message to companies who make unusable products by boycotting them. I knew very well I was breaking this rule when I signed up. But much like the early days of email, when people would ask “What’s your email address?”, everyone started asking “Where’s your MySpace profile?”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pay Day</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/pay_day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/pay_day/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.portfolio.com/infographics/2007/06/salary_comparison">&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/08/ceo-salaries.gif' alt='Increasing salaries of the CEO' class="image-centered" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s apparently a good time to be the CEO, according to &lt;a href="http://www.portfolio.com/infographics/2007/06/salary_comparison">Portfolio.com&lt;/a>. Most recently CEOs have been making 465 times the salary of their average worker. Compared to only 28 times in 1970.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this sums up the response to that age old interview question of where you want to be in 5, 10, or 15 years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning From The 50mm Experience</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/learning_from_the_50mm_experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 13:20:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/learning_from_the_50mm_experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a photography hobbyist, always have a camera in my bag. I’ve got lenses that range from 18mm to 135mm in zoom length and they all suit me pretty well–&lt;em>still on the look out for an ultra wide but that’s besides the point&lt;/em>. Every now and then I find myself coming back to my 50mm prime lens (no variable zoom, it is what it is). I can only explain this due to that there is something about working within a specific set of constraints which inspires me. With no ability to stand in place and twist a zoom ring to adjust the frame of my photo, I’m on my feet a lot more getting closer to objects, standing on whatever is accessible. To put it plainly, I feel that I’m more creative with my shooting–less susceptible to that dilemma of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_theory#Paradox_of_choice">greatness in choice&lt;/a>. I have to work with what I’m given.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac People Japan</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/mac_people_japan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 19:55:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/mac_people_japan/</guid><description>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/08/mac-people.jpg' alt='Mac People Japan' class="image-centered" />
&lt;p>Almost 10 years ago a startup screen which my brother Mike and I had designed was featured in the Japanese magazine &lt;em>Mac People&lt;/em>. When I was approached to have the startup screen featured in the magazine and included on their CD, I had requested that they send me a copy of the issue. Long after my exuberance about being in a magazine at age 15 had passed, having assumed they passed on including our work, a package from Japan filled our mailbox.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>By The Way, You Just Learned How To Click</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/by_the_way_you_just_learned_how_to_click/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 13:39:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/by_the_way_you_just_learned_how_to_click/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.macmothership.com/gallery/gallery3.html">&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/08/test-drive-mac.jpg' alt='Test Drive the Macintosh. Learn to use a mouse' class="image-centered" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instructions on how to operate a mouse are fairly rare these days. But there was a time when the mouse was a new method of interaction and we had to inform people on the mechanics of its operation. In a 1984 Apple &lt;a href="http://www.macmothership.com/gallery/gallery3.html">brochure&lt;/a> for the Macintosh they outlined how to use a mouse and what it could be used for. Reading it today, it sounds like a set of directions for something as pedestrian as a door handle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Art of Being Ambiguous While Recruiting</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/the_art_of_being_ambiguous_while_recruiting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 12:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/08/the_art_of_being_ambiguous_while_recruiting/</guid><description>&lt;p>User experience professionals seem to be in fairly good demand it appears. I only say this due to the amount of recruiter calls I receive. Typically 1 every other day. Lately though they have really stepped it up–calling my mobile phone, calling my office phone (by way of dialing the company switchboard), and emailing me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone gets the call saying that a friend or colleague had referred them and by the way they want to remain anonymous. But recently I got a call that topped that them all simply by being as ambiguous as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ZipDog</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/zipdog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/zipdog/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src='http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/zip-dog.gif' alt='ZipDog' class="image-right" />My old college roommate, &lt;a href="http://kevsull.spaces.live.com">Kevin&lt;/a>, sent me a link today about a &lt;a href="http://www.boston.com/business/globe/articles/2007/07/30/service_lets_you_pay_for_time_with_a_dog____but_dont_call_it_rent_a_pet/">story&lt;/a> of a woman who has started a pet rental service called &lt;a href="http://www.flexpetz.com/">Flex Petz&lt;/a>. While in school Kevin and I, fond users of the ZipCar service, often joked about the idea of creating a company around the same model but with dogs–ZipDog (aptly named for the assumed buyout offer from ZipCar that was surely to come).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea was simple; not many people want to own a dog or can’t due to building rules, but do like to play with them. We envisioned package deals with ZipCar for weekend getaways to the beach where you not only rented the car but also a friendly companion to throw the frisbee around with. Most people balked at the idea, citing many reasons as far as people renting dogs simply to abuse them. All issues aside, it certainly was a missed business opportunity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stretch Your TV, Stretch Your Web TV</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/stretch_your_tv_stretch_your_web_tv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/stretch_your_tv_stretch_your_web_tv/</guid><description>&lt;p>You almost can’t buy a TV today that isn’t a widescreen, yet the majority of our TV programming is still broadcasted in the traditional 4:3 aspect ratio (square shape) format. But you’ve got that nice widescreen tv so you got to use that all too common stretch feature, which more often than not produces a poor image and is not at all flattering for our favorite celebrities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was originally designed to be a feature to handle legacy content is unnecessarily making its way to the web. &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/">CNN&lt;/a>, who broadcasts in 4:3, has just recently updated their web site and has implemented a new &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/video/">video player&lt;/a>. Oddly, they have opted to replicate this stretching effect on their web site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The IA Portfolio Dilemma</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/the_ia_portfoli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 13:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/07/the_ia_portfoli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having recently listened to the NYC CHI talk on UX career paths, I heard some interesting revelations on the perceptions of IA portfolios and gauging ability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The greatest issue with IA portfolios seems to be that an IA can do many different things and as such their deliverables can be an assortment of artifacts. We see everything from a swath of wireframes to requirements documents and sitemaps, possibly personas or interaction flows–all of which are not necessarily glitzy. There is no one set of expected portfolio elements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GMaps Street View leaves New Yorkers with Much to Desire</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/05/gmaps_streetvie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/05/gmaps_streetvie/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google has just released, &lt;em>Street View&lt;/em>, its latest feature to the Google Maps product. Essentially an enhanced version of Amazon A9’s now defunct block view. While impressive, I could not help but notice the lack of image quality of the panoramas. Although surprisingly, it seems this is a New York specific issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shown below are two views of Apple’s stores in both &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=1+Stockton+St&amp;amp;sll=37.785915,-122.406299&amp;amp;sspn=0.001664,0.001896&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=37.786333,-122.406036&amp;amp;spn=0.001664,0.002776&amp;amp;z=19&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=37.785821,-122.406221&amp;amp;cbp=1,278.796237348706,0.224027323783593,3">San Francisco&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=767+Fifth+Ave.+new+york+ny&amp;amp;sll=37.786333,-122.406152&amp;amp;sspn=0.001645,0.001658&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=40.764236,-73.973238&amp;amp;spn=0.001576,0.001658&amp;amp;z=19&amp;amp;om=1&amp;amp;layer=c&amp;amp;cbll=40.763939,-73.973264&amp;amp;cbp=1,115.294117647059,0.45281862745098,2">New York City&lt;/a>; of note is the difference in image quality between the two. San Francisco Street Views also have another additional level of zoom detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Would You Like a Receipt?</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/01/would_you_like/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 14:01:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2007/01/would_you_like/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prompting users about whether they would like to receive a receipt upon completing an ATM transaction is a long common practice. As is the practice of after printing one, immediately throwing it away. How are users interacting with these receipts and what can be done to reduce the waste as well as provide an easier and more secure experience?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through examining ATM environments and the methods in which users interact with ATMs we can gain insightful details, especially around how receipts are used. To begin though, we must look at what types of information are provided on an ATM receipt; usually bank name, time, location, withdrawal/deposit amount, and account balance. These receipts often don’t travel very far from their birthplace–usually right into a trash can, which has been neatly placed at the foot of the ATM. Also in an odd bit of anthropological examination it is interesting to see how users dispose of their receipts; sometimes they are simply placed in the trash can, other times they’re crumpled up or even torn up into bits. The later methods appear to be some form of rudimentary security implementation (I must confess that out of habit I too tear my receipts up).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Design Challenge</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2006/04/the_design_chal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2006 18:09:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2006/04/the_design_chal/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently thinking about how to exercise my mind to force myself out of the daily routine and came up with a challenge. Redesign any commonly used object.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn’t a ground breaking concept, but I think it’s an interesting method to keep yourself thinking and looking at how you interact with objects in your environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The redesign is to be quick and dirty, rough sketches, nothing too elaborate–focusing more on the idea than the delivery. There is no guideline as to what the redesign is to acheive, it may be increased usability, it may just be to look prettier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mobile Monday New York</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2006/03/mobile_mondays/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2006 19:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2006/03/mobile_mondays/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I was asked to speak at the &lt;a href="http://mobilemonday-ny.com/">Mobile Monday&lt;/a> series in New York on the research I had worked on around text entry methods. It’s nice to see events such as these popping up, as it seems this field is under-represented by the professional design and usability organizations (upa, chi, ixda, etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The topic for the Mobile Monday event I spoke at was all about design and usability of mobile devices. Coming from a more research background it was interesting to see the other presenters talking about work which they have done that has actually made it into products.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Scent to Pagination</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/11/adding_scent_to/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/11/adding_scent_to/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spanning search results or any other kind of list of information across pages has become standard fare on the Web. Unfortunately this information is now secretly locked behind mystery doors (links) 2 through 34. How can we give the user insight into what lies behind these doors instead of simply choosing at random in order to find they information they desire?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pagination has helped in reducing the load of information a user has to take in or download for that matter, but the pagination navigation leaves a great deal to be desired. Typically the pagination navigation is simply a list of linked numbers which reference each page of results, sometimes truncated to reduce an overload of page links. The problem with this is that the user is essentially gambling with what he will be presented with when clicking on a page link. Which is why most users don’t actually randomly pick a page, they walk through the results with the &lt;em>Next Page&lt;/em> link.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the Tag Cloud Through Color</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/10/improving_the_t/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2005 21:14:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/10/improving_the_t/</guid><description>&lt;p>I know, why are we still talking about tag clouds? The concept is becoming a bit cliche as of late, but they’re still a viable option for presenting information visually. Although, a problem with tag clouds seems to be that their scaling ability is limited. But there are ways to improve its scalability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an avid &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr&lt;/a> (king of tag clouds) user, you can imagine my &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bhaggs/tags/">list of photo tags&lt;/a> is getting larger over time. Thus the tag cloud which represents my photo tags is becoming increasingly difficult to quickly acquire comparative information of my tags, based soley on font size.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iTunes Login Confusion</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/09/itunes_login_co/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 18:33:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/09/itunes_login_co/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you use Apple’s iTunes Music Store you’ve probably had that moment of confusion when attempting to decipher the iTunes login prompt. What was meant to be a simple option of choosing whether your account is from Apple or AOL has led users to have to more closely evaluate what is being asked of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The login prompt, displayed in figure 1, goes against the typical linear fashion of form entry. Account type options are listed vertically alongside the username and password fields. Without any presentational separation or field label for the &lt;em>account type&lt;/em>, the form is read from left to right and top to bottom. Figure 2 outlines how the current format is typically perceived by the user when scanning the form. The user is given the impression that the username field may only belong to the Apple radio button and password to the AOL radio button.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tennis Balls and Walkers, an Ultimate User Hack</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/09/tennis_balls_an/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2005 22:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/09/tennis_balls_an/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is almost a rarity to see a person with a walker which does not have the signature tennis balls on the back legs. The users of these walkers have filled a gap in the design to make the walker better fit their needs. But the real question is, why haven’t the designers of the walker taken notice of this very prominent “user hack”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a designer it is always fascinating to see how the users actually interacts with your design. This also poses as a means of feedback and a way to learn more about how users push the design. Typically the activity of listening to users’ feedback and observing their interactions is reincorporated back into the design process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don’t Change that Dial</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/08/dont_change_tha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 20:58:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/08/dont_change_tha/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently heard a radio advertisement proclaiming, “Don’t change that dial”, a fairly common phrase in radio advertising. But as technology advances (eliminating dials in favor of buttons), sayings such as the aforementioned one are becoming irrelevant. This same progression is occurring in the metaphors we use in computing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the first graphical user interfaces were being developed the designers sought to ease the learning curve by making the user experience similar to one which they already knew–the desktop. Such a metaphor was an ideal implemenation. The computer interface contained all the familiar elements of that of a desktop–files, folders, sticky notes, a desktop workspace, and a trash can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Job, New People, New York City</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/07/new_job_new_peo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2005 11:11:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/07/new_job_new_peo/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Saturday, July 30th, I will be leaving Boston on a one-way trip down to New York City. Next week I start my new job at JPMorgan Chase in Midtown Manhattan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At &lt;a href="http://www.jpmorganchase.com">JPMorgan Chase&lt;/a> I will be working as a user interface designer and information architect within the Global Credit Risk Management division (that sounds so much more complex in writing). I will be the fourth member of the User Experience group. From what I have gathered from my conversations and meetings with them they are very friendly and chill people–much like how I see myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’ve Been Robbed</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/06/ive_been_robbed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 13:55:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/06/ive_been_robbed/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s Sunday afternoon, there are clear skies with a high of 92°. A bit hot for my tastes but I’ve had a good weekend. I am looking forward to taking a shower, watching some TV, and getting some work done on the computer. Only to arrive home and discover that I was robbed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I expected my arrival at my apartment to be no different than any other time I’ve come home after staying over at Neera’s place. This time around it began just like that–nothing seeming out of the ordinary, Moz (my cat) hanging out in the living room, some stuff moved about due to Kevin moving. It wasn’t until I walked into my bedroom that I was a little tweaked out. Some of my drawers were pulled out–meanwhile I’m thinking, “Man, if you need some stamps or something at least close the drawer.” Then I notice my PowerBook is gone. Still, at this point I have this feeling that maybe someone was using it in the living room or something.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catering to Users’ Styles</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/06/catering_to_use/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2005 18:47:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/06/catering_to_use/</guid><description>&lt;p>A major part of design for any medium is clearly understanding its audience. &lt;a href="http://www.gap.com">Gap&lt;/a> clothing understands this and is tailoring their stores to better fit with what their customers expect to get out of a shopping experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the clothing industry knowing what the customers like and what their methods for shopping are is critical for profitability. In terms of shopping methods, the major unisex stores such as Gap, H&amp;amp;M, and Urban Outfitters pretty much use a one size fits all model for merchandise placement–one which predominantly falls in line with how women shop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off to California</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/05/off_to_californ/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2005 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/05/off_to_californ/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tomorrow, Neera and I will be heading out on a multiple destination trip in the sunny state of California. While the intended purpose for visiting is to attend a wedding, we have turned the trip into a reason to go on vacation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="figure-right">
 &lt;a href="http://www.trekearth.com/gallery/North_America/United_States/photo88167.htm">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/sf-gg-bridge.jpg" alt="Golden Gate bridge in the forefront under fog with the San Francisco skyline in the background" height="187" width="300" />&lt;/a>&lt;br /> &lt;em>San Francisco’s Golden Gate Bridge under fog&lt;/em>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our first California destination is the city of San Francisco. I’ve heard a lot of great things about the city and surrounding areas. As a fan of transit systems I’m definitely interested in checking out the BART and the touristy old time trolleys. In fact, we’ll be riding public transportation to the &lt;a href="http://www.anchorbrewing.com/">Anchor Brewery&lt;/a> for a guided tour of their uniquely San Franciscan brewery. Luckily we’ll have a local, one of Neera’s college friends, showing us around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guiding the User with Contextual Help</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/05/guiding_the_use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2005 13:49:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/05/guiding_the_use/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a &lt;a href="http://www.paypal.com">PayPal&lt;/a> user I frequently use it to pay for products or services when available, as it is easier than pulling out the credit card. Recently, while renewing a domain name at &lt;a href="http://www.godaddy.com">GoDaddy&lt;/a> using &lt;em>PayPal&lt;/em> I ran into an unfamiliar form request. Unfortunately &lt;em>GoDaddy&lt;/em> does not provide easily accessible explanations to such requests. Situations such as these are ideal for contextual help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The form request in question is displayed below in Figure 1.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The End of the Northeastern Era</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/the_end_of_the/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2005 14:10:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/the_end_of_the/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I finished my last exam of my undergraduate career. Next Saturday, my five years at &lt;a href="http://www.neu.edu">Northeastern University&lt;/a> will culminate with graduation at the Boston Garden (formerly the FleetCenter). Where I will go from here, is still very much in the air–industry, academia, New York, California, or just staying right here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="a-brief-look-back">A Brief Look Back&lt;/h4>
&lt;p class="figure-right">
 &lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/freshman-bryan.jpg" alt="Self portrait of Bryan Haggerty, freshman year of college" height="204" width="204" />&lt;br /> &lt;em>Me during my freshman year&lt;/em>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the fall of 2000, when I brought that first cart load into &lt;a href="http://www.housing.neu.edu/see_stetsonW.html">Stetson West&lt;/a>, 2005 seemed a great ways off. Much like today, seeing the banner for “Welcome Class of 2010” seems like a far off time. I look at this picture of me taken for COM1121 (freshman intro class for Co-Op) and am shocked at how young I feel like I look–considering how these past five years seem like such a blur at this point. (For comparison here is a &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/about/index.php">recent photo&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHI 2005: Day 3 – The Conference Begins</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2005 02:03:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_3/</guid><description>&lt;p>With attendees fashioning wearable computers and discovering that other people, independently of myself, were taking pictures of the &lt;a href="http://www.trimet.org">MAX’s&lt;/a> accessibility features, it was apparent that CHI was in town. Today the CHI conference’s main events began, featuring presentations on full and short papers, interactive expositions, and companies show their wares and recruiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="opening-plenary">Opening Plenary&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.etc.cmu.edu/~pausch/">Randy Pausch&lt;/a> of &lt;a href="http://www.cmu.edu">CMU&lt;/a> opened the conference with a powerful talk on pushing for greater interdisciplinary work. Although, his talk overall was laden with hints at how great CMU is–not to say that was a bad thing. Randy showcased a lot of great work that they were doing, projects which are way beyond what our lab could do at this time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHI 2005: Day 2 – Exploring the City</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 01:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_2/</guid><description>&lt;p>We were up and about early today to get what appears to be our only day for exploring the city of Portland. Luckily the weather provided a mild sunny day as the backdrop for our trek throughout the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="downtown-portland">Downtown Portland&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Portland has turned out to be more urban than I had thought. Being a more modern city, in relation to Boston, the urban planning made getting around quite easy. I still cannot get over how much Iâ€™m in love with &lt;a href="http://www.trimet.org">Tri-Met&lt;/a> (Portland’s public transit system). Some of their methods probably would not work in Boston, such as the honor system based fare collection. But, at the very least I think Tri-Met employees actually enjoy their jobs and want to help their customers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHI 2005: Day 1 – Arrival in Portland</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2005 01:40:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/04/chi_2005_day_1/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a bit of an ordeal with flights, today we arrived in “green” Portland Oregon. While only being able to do a limited amount of exploring, it seems that Portland has a lot going on. Pre-conference events have begun and there is certainly an HCI vibe pouring out into the streets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="flight-madness">Flight Madness&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Upon arriving at Logan airport this morning for my 7:35 Northwest Airlines flight I was informed of a delay, which in turn meant I would miss my connecting flight. Northwest booked me on an American Airlines flight but I had little time to get from terminal E to terminal B. Just my luck too, I was detained for additional screening at security. Fortunately, I made it to the gate for last call.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHI 2005: Off to Portland Oregon</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/chi_2005_off_to/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2005 21:43:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/chi_2005_off_to/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.neu.edu">Northeastern University’s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.ccs.neu.edu">College of Computer and Information Science&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.ccs.neu.edu/research/hci/">&lt;acronym title="Human-Computer Interaction">HCI&lt;/acronym> Research Lab&lt;/a>, a lab I’m a part of, is headed off to Portland, OR for the &lt;a href="http://www.chi2005.org">&lt;acronym title="Computer-Human Interaction">CHI&lt;/acronym>&lt;/a> conference to present some of our most recent research work. Aside from attending the presentations and networking with colleagues, hopefully I’ll get a chance to check out the &lt;a href="http://www.travelportland.com/">Portland&lt;/a> area.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="what-is-chi-and-what-are-we-doing-there">What is CHI and What are We Doing There?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote cite="http://www.chi2005.org/">
 &lt;p>
 CHI 2005 is the premier international conference for human-computer interaction.
 &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MyNeu Listens to Feedback</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/myneu_listens_t/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2005 14:18:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/myneu_listens_t/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reaching out of the development bubble to learn how users feel about and use an application or service can provide useful insight. It sounds like an obvious idea, but it is not always commonly done. Luckily it seems that &lt;a href="http://www.neu.edu">Northeastern University&lt;/a> is getting closer to realizing the benefits of such a method.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the course of two years I have identified some key areas of Northeastern’s &lt;a href="http://myneu.neu.edu">&lt;em>MyNeu&lt;/em>&lt;/a> student portal system which I felt were hindering the overall user experience (readings available in the &lt;a href="#related-links" title="Read other articles I've written about this topic">Related Links&lt;/a> section). I had mailed my original research paper to Northeastern’s Information Services department in hopes of creating a dialogue to discuss ways to improve the &lt;em>MyNeu&lt;/em> user experience. Nothing came of my efforts so I ultimately left it at that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Augmenting Google Maps with Landmarks</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/augmenting_goog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2005 18:25:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/augmenting_goog/</guid><description>&lt;p>The introduction of &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com">Google Maps&lt;/a> provided a major push in innovating the online maps and directions services, which in turn has opened up new avenues for further innovation in this sector. Introducing visual representations of landmarks within directions can hopefully improve the success rates of correctly following directions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="cognitive-maps">Cognitive Maps&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Research in cognitive psychology suggests that the way in which humans determine position and get around their environments is based upon a construct known as cognitive maps. Such maps can be seen as a mental representation of a person’s surroundings, typically loosely constructed and centering on relationships between landmarks (i.e., buildings, unique objects, etc).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Innovating Online Travel Sites</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/innovating_onli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2005 12:16:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/innovating_onli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Competition is stiff in the online travel site business and usability innovations will be a great factor in determining the top sites. &lt;a href="http://www.aol.com">AOL&lt;/a> has recently released a beta version of its new &lt;a href="http://www.pinpointtravel.com">&lt;em>Pinpoint Travel&lt;/em>&lt;/a> service. With the user in mind they have developed a simple and easy to use Web site which effectively works with the user. Highlighted are areas of novel design strategies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="goal-oriented-design">Goal-Oriented Design&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Users come to a travel site such as &lt;em>Pinpoint Travel&lt;/em> with a specific goal in mind, find cheap flights, quickly and easily. &lt;em>Pinpoint Travel&lt;/em> brings this goal to the foreground with an interesting technique. As can be seen in this &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/pinpoint-goals.php">Accompanying Screenshot&lt;/a>, once a user has focused on the flight search box all other elements are faded into the background. Conveying to the user that this is the primary area to be interacting with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conveying Information Visually</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/conveying_infor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2005 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/conveying_infor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Various research has proven that people do not read the Web in the same manner which they would read a book or a magazine. In the fast paced Web, people are task oriented, relying on quickly scanning Web pages to find their desired information. Conveying information in a visual manner can help augment this form of information retrieval.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.37signals.com/" title="Visit 37Signals">37Signals’&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.tadalist.com/">&lt;em>Ta-Da Lists&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, a Web-based to-do list application, provides users with a simple visual cue to show approximately how many items are in a particular list. List bullets enlarge in accordance to the amount of items contained. Figure 1 shows how a user can quickly attain useful information merely by glancing at the page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS, Its Overload, and the Web Browser</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/rss_its_overloa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2005 20:21:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/03/rss_its_overloa/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the adoption rate of RSS and news aggregators increases it is interesting to see how people’s use of the Web changes because of this simple technology. Although, are we approaching information overload? Is this a technology which average users can use? And more importantly, does the Web browser need to change to incorporate this new method of Web browsing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="handling-the-overload">Handling the Overload&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As I sit here typing this I currently have &lt;strong>251&lt;/strong> unread articles in my news aggregator. More often than not I end up hitting the &lt;em>Mark All as Read&lt;/em> button at the end of the day. Not because I’m not interested in those articles but more so that there is a lot of noise. The news aggregator acts as an aggregator of link aggregators, so you get the point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look at Google Maps</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/02/google_maps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2005 16:03:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/02/google_maps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google’s recently released Maps beta is likely to be considered more innovative than their GMail product. Especially when looking at the markets for each product. While GMail provided an unheard of, at the time, 1gb of storage, the competition quickly responded. This isn’t to say that GMail didn’t have an assortment of other great features, but with &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com">Google Maps&lt;/a> they have completely changed the online map paradigm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="figure-centered">
 &lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/gmaps-overview.jpg" alt="Google Maps Overview" height="210" width="450" />&lt;br /> Figure 1. The new Google Maps.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My History on the Web</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/02/my_history_on_t/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2005 17:18:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/02/my_history_on_t/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the past 10 years I have made my mark on the Web in some fashion. Whether it was my PC bashing Mac centric homepage of the mid-90s, the rave fueled &lt;em>Haggs 2.0&lt;/em>, or the currently professionally focused &lt;em>Losing Context&lt;/em>, I have a history on the Web. With the remodeling of Losing Context I decided to provide a little insight into the past of my time on the Web.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="1995">1995&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>My first foray into the Web should be prefaced with a piece I wrote back in ’96 about learning &lt;acronym title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML&lt;/acronym> and my proficiency in making web pages:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Example of Inconsistent &amp;amp; Poor Form Design</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/01/effects_of_inco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2005 20:32:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2005/01/effects_of_inco/</guid><description>&lt;p>Web applications are becoming more and more prominent, as are the html forms which comprise the method of interaction for these applications. Through the use of a simple example, I’ll discuss some of the good and bad points behind this example’s form design in terms of instructions and form actions. Additionally I’ll cover some tips on how to identify and avoid these problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently came across a simple example of inconsistent form design at the &lt;a href="http://www.salliemae.com/" title="See the example for yourself">SallieMae&lt;/a> website. Due to that I rarely login to this particular website I needed to find out what my &lt;em>user ID&lt;/em> and &lt;em>password&lt;/em> were. To attain this information it is necessary to access both their &lt;em>Forgot user ID&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Forgot password&lt;/em> forms. Two very simple forms, let’s take a closer look into the components of the forms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doing More with Photos</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/12/doing_more_with/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2004 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/12/doing_more_with/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been a lot of talk about &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com" title="Check out the Flickr service">Flickr&lt;/a> lately, but what I found the most intriguing is seeing how people are using it. The central component of the service is its ability to allow people to finally share their digital photos in a more easy and natural manner. It is pretty common for me, and many people I know, to take digital photographs and then do absolutely nothing with them. Since the onset of digital photography this problem has been sought to be solved by a multitude of different software applications and services. So what are they doing wrong and why is &lt;em>Flickr&lt;/em> a step in the right direction?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never, Never, Land</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/11/never_never_lan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2004 17:33:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/11/never_never_lan/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?playListId=27505231&amp;amp;originStoreFront=143441" title="Check out this album on iTunes">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/unkle-nnl.jpg" alt="UNKLE - Never, Never, Land" class="image-right" border="0" height="150" width="150" />&lt;/a> UNKLE’s latest album, which apparently took me awhile to get, goes in a new direction in comparison to the first album which featured DJ Shadow as a major player. &lt;a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?playListId=27505231&amp;amp;originStoreFront=143441" title="Check out this album on iTunes">&lt;em>Never, Never, Land&lt;/em>&lt;/a>–masterminded by James Lavelle, Richard File, &lt;del>DJ Shadow&lt;/del>–utilizes many pianos and strings which give it an almost trip-hop like feel. Much like UNKLE’s first album, &lt;em>Psyence Fiction&lt;/em>, there is an assortment of guest artists who make up many of the vocals on the tracks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Misuse of the PDF</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/11/the_misuse_of_t/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2004 15:38:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/11/the_misuse_of_t/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;acronym title="Portable Document Format">PDF&lt;/acronym> format has many merits for its use–standardized formatting, easy production and publishing. But it seems that today it is being abused as a means of bypassing having to write a web page formatted in &lt;acronym title="HyperText Markup Language">HTML&lt;/acronym>. More and more frequently I see companies forgoing this task of writing a web page and just tossing up their content in a downloadable PDF file. It is now so prevalent on the web that search engines such as &lt;a href="http://www.google.com">Google&lt;/a> have opted to add PDF content to their index.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MyNeu: Problems with Icon Design</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/10/myneu_problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2004 16:04:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/10/myneu_problems/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/myneu-icons.gif" alt="MyNeu Icons" class="image-right" border="0" height="201" width="291" />In user interface design icons play a major role, as they provide the user with a simple visual cue intended to easily convey the meaning of a feature or action at a glance. Icon design in web applications is especially paramount as web users typically scan pages as opposed to actively reading them. The choice of icons can greatly affect how users interact with a web application and ultimately the usability of such an application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bank Square</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/10/bank_square/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2004 19:03:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/10/bank_square/</guid><description>&lt;p class="figure-centered">
 &lt;img alt="Harvard Square Banks" src="http://www.losingcontext.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/harvard-bank-map.jpg" width="450" height="177" border="0" />&lt;br /> Figure 1. &lt;em>Map of Banks in Harvard Square&lt;/em>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since my term ended at &lt;a href="http://www.harvard.edu">Harvard&lt;/a> my time in the &lt;a href="http://www.harvardsquare.com" title="Get information about happenings in the square">Harvard Square&lt;/a> area has dropped off significantly. Recently I ventured back through to meet up with some old co-workers. I was literally floored by what I saw. Harvard Square is becoming so commercialized and now exists mainly as a marketing tool for companies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Boston area banks have destroyed the culture of Harvard Square by invading its every space. Upon walking out of the &lt;a href="http://www.mbta.com">MBTA&lt;/a> station you have access to six full service banks all within eyeshot. It’s not about taking in the history and atmosphere of Harvard, it’s about taking in the brand.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women Love the iPod Mini</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/women_love_the/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 16:19:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/women_love_the/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipodmini/" title="Learn more about the iPod mini">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/ipod-mini.jpg" alt="iPod mini" class="image-right" border="0" height="257" width="138" />&lt;/a>No where else have I seen more &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipod/" title="Learn more about the iPod">iPod&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipodmini/" title="Learn more about the iPod mini">Minis&lt;/a> than on the women of &lt;a href="http://www.neu.edu" title="Learn more about Northeastern University">Northeastern&lt;/a> campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why has the iPod mini become such a success when all the technology pundits hailed it an instant failure when Apple announced it?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-the-technology-pundits-were-wrong">Why the Technology Pundits Were Wrong&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The majority of those commenting on technology are men. I myself questioned Apple’s decision with the iPod mini. It looked cool but the price and capacity just were not enticing to me. There in lies where the failure speculation occurred, like me, other men saw the same faults. But we all seemed to forget that not just gadget geeks use these devices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working Hang Outs</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/working_hang_ou/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2004 19:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/working_hang_ou/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the Fall semester of school already underway you can probably tell by the lack of updates that I have been inundated with work. Currently I’m working on a few projects which include a fair amount of writing; pleading for grant money and asking for acceptance to conferences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I have found myself lately hanging out at various places doing work because at my apartment there are just too many distractions. So I just felt that I should give thanks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Innovating the Mobile Phone</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/innovating_the/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2004 10:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/innovating_the/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.nokia.com/nokia/0,,62750,00.html" title="Read the press release">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/nokia-hs-13w.jpg" alt="Nokia HS-13w" class="image-right" border="0" height="298" width="163" />&lt;/a>About a year ago I had come up with an idea where your watch communicated with your mobile phone, via bluetooth, to display information such as caller id. The reasoning is that I hate having to pull out my mobile phone all the time to see who is calling. I also frequently leave my phone at my desk which sometimes puts me out of range to hear the phone or forces me to run to my phone just to see that it is a phone call that I don’t want to take.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPod: The Ultimate DJ</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/ipod_the_ultima/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2004 16:03:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/09/ipod_the_ultima/</guid><description>&lt;p>More often than not I find myself feeling that my &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipod/" title="Learn more about the iPod">iPod&lt;/a> knows what kind of mood I’m in. As an avid user of the &lt;em>Random&lt;/em> feature I leave the DJing up to my iPod and it continually impresses me by its track selection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I know the random feature works entirely by mathematics I am frequently shocked at how well the iPod comes up with a musical set which is tailored to my mood and activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Post Road Pumpkin Ale</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/post_road_pumpk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2004 21:40:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/post_road_pumpk/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.brooklynbrewery.com/beers.asp?OID=18" title="Learn more about Post Road's Pumpkin Ale.">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/post-road-pumpkin-ale.jpg" alt="Post Road Pumpkin Ale" class="image-right" border="0" height="137" width="150" />&lt;/a>I recently picked up Post Road’s [&lt;em>a &lt;a href="http://www.brooklynbrewery.com/" title="The Brooklyn Brewery web site">Brooklyn Brewery&lt;/a> brand&lt;/em>] &lt;a href="http://www.brooklynbrewery.com/beers.asp?OID=18" title="Learn more about Post Road's Pumpkin Ale.">Pumpkin Ale&lt;/a>. I had sought to find an uncommon beer, something that was not the standard ale fare of today’s beers. Lately I have found myself craving the award winning Harpoon &lt;a href="http://www.harpoonbrewery.com/beers/harpoon/winterwarmer.htm" title="Learn more about Harpoon's Winter Warmer">Winter Warmer&lt;/a>. I don’t know if it is due to that I am burnt out on Sam Adams’ Summer Ale or if I am just ready for Fall to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Revolution is Now</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/the_revolution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2004 21:17:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/the_revolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0060761555/qid=1093137176/sr=ka-1/ref=pd_ka_1/102-2250452-6806553" title="Check out this book at Amazon">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/the-revolution.jpg" alt="The Revolution Will Not Be Televised" class="image-right" border="0" height="227" width="150" />&lt;/a> The Dean campaign is what got me into seriously following politics as opposed to just watching the headlines and never really scratching the surface of where our country is going. When I first saw how Howard Dean was taking politics in a different direction, and using what is considered to be an unconventional political tool–the Internet–I was ultimately curious. Mainly due to that I am avidly interested in technology and beginning to question where we as Americans fit into deciding our government.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amazon.com: Work In Progress</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/amazoncom_work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2004 00:28:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/amazoncom_work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/amazon-work.gif" alt="Amazon.com: Work In Progress" class="image-right" border="0" height="46" width="115" />I recently ordered a few books from Amazon and like many people have found them to be a great online store. While waiting for my packages to arrive I decided to check the status of my delivery. A lagged page load brought to my attention a few problems with Amazon and subsequently others upon investigation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="there-is-an-alternative">There is an ALTernative?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Amazon has been praised by many critics as providing users with one of the best user experiences and I agree with this statement on most levels. But there are still many major problems which have simple solutions that lurk throughout the site, even the home page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taking On CSS</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/taking_on_css/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2004 10:44:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/taking_on_css/</guid><description>&lt;p>It seems that more and more people are showing some interest in learning &lt;acronym title="Cascading Style Sheets">CSS&lt;/acronym> and &lt;acronym title="eXtensible HyperText Markup Language">XHTML&lt;/acronym> but don’t seem to know where to get useful information about it. There’s a lot out there, and you can spend a few hours searching Google just to find out that you haven’t learned much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://9rules.com/whitespace/" title="Visit Whitespace">Whitespace&lt;/a> has posted an &lt;a href="http://9rules.com/whitespace/design/learning_css.php" title="Whitespace Article: Learning CSS">article&lt;/a> with a lot of good resources on how to get into using CSS and XHTML and even what to do after you think you’ve mastered the two. If you’re seriously looking to make the jump from 1997 to today check out the provided resources from Whitespace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating User-Friendly URLs</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/creating_userfr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2004 10:59:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/08/creating_userfr/</guid><description>&lt;p>The web is rampant with crude looking URLs largely due to the increase of dynamically generated web pages. Not only do these URLs look poor visually they decrease a site’s usability and become less attractive to search engines for ranking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll take a look at why these URLs are a problem and how they can be fixed to present a friendlier user experience and improve your search rankings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="usability-of-urls">Usability of URLs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ever try to tell someone a URL over the phone or attempt to write down a specific URL? Aside from the domain name, things can get real hairy after that first trailing slash. Somewhere along the line, we as developers have seemed to forget what the URL is supposed to tell the user.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dating File Relaunch</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/dating_file_rel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2004 16:46:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/dating_file_rel/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.thedatingfile.com" title="Visit The Dating File.com">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/new-tdf.jpg" alt="The Dating File Revamped" class="image-right" border="0" height="177" width="200" />&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.foursedgewick.com" title="Visit the FourSedgewick Interactive web site">FourSedgewick Interactive&lt;/a> has been hard at work revamping &lt;a href="http://www.thedatingfile.com" title="Visit The Dating File.com">The Dating File&lt;/a> and bringing it back to life. After a long hiatus we’re ready to bring the site back with a souped up engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The release brings along a new standards compliant design featuring XHTML 1.0 Transitional and CSS 2. As well as prominent use of &lt;acronym title="Portable Network Graphics">PNGs&lt;/acronym> and alpha-transparencies. In order to discuss the benefits of standards compliant design I’ve provided a bit of analysis between the version 4 site and the newly released version 5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Buffalo Trip part 2</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/buffalo_trip_pa_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2004 12:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/buffalo_trip_pa_1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bhaggs/tags/niagara/" title="View my photos from Niagra">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/niagara-falls.jpg" alt="Niagara Falls" class="image-right" border="0" height="113" width="200" />&lt;/a>Got a little recap of the tail end of my trip to Buffalo, NY. Myself, Neera, and her mom headed up to Niagara Canada to check out Niagara-on-the-Lake, the &lt;a href="http://www.niagaraparks.com/nature/butterfly.php" title="Learn more about the Butteryfly Conservatory">Butterfly Conservatory&lt;/a>, and the Falls at night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was good to see some of the other aspects of the Niagara area since I had already seen the Falls previously. The Butterfly Conservatory was an amazing sight to see. They’re tough to get a picture of unless if you have a high speed camera.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Buffalo Trip part 1</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/buffalo_trip_pa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2004 22:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/buffalo_trip_pa/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a nasty rainstorm and a bit of traffic we finally arrived in Buffalo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today we headed into the city and got some &lt;em>chicken finger subs&lt;/em>, a Buffalo speciality, and cruised around the city. I’ll give Buffalo credit for one thing, its got a lot of unique shops, something that is quickly fading away in Boston. Granted many of these shops only offered womens trinkets (candles, soaps, etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also got to check out Buffalo’s subway system in some degree. Unfortunately it is not something to write home about, but since I dig transit systems I will. Pretty much it has stops in the all the places you don’t want to go. From what I can gather the people are afraid of the thing. If you bring a subway stop to a thriving area, it will kill it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Off to Buffalo</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/off_to_buffalo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2004 17:47:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/off_to_buffalo/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="A poor representation of Buffalo" src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/buffalo.jpg" width="200" height="138" border="0" class="image-right" />Neera and I are heading out to &lt;a href="http://www.ci.buffalo.ny.us/" title="Learn more about Buffalo">Buffalo&lt;/a> New York for the weekend. For the most part just a trip to hang out, get out of Boston, and for her to visit home. The big thing on my mind is the wings though. You would think that the wing recipe could be replicated, but none can come close to authentic &lt;em>Buffalo Wings&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our itinerary is pretty much non-existant, which is totally fine with me. Although we are thinking we might head up to Toronto for a day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The new age of software development</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/the_new_age_of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2004 15:07:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/the_new_age_of/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve come across a few good articles which I think are worth reading if you are interested in software development and in particular how rich client programming is declining as web client programming is increasing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joel Spolsky has written a lengthy analysis of &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/APIWar.html" title="Read Joel's article">How Microsoft Lost the API War&lt;/a>. It definitely opened my eyes a bit as it discusses some of Microsoft’s missteps and just plainly how the industry is changing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Up Up Down Down Left Right Left Right B A Select Start</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/up_up_down_down/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2004 00:28:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/up_up_down_down/</guid><description>&lt;p>People seem to be going 8-bit crazy these days. From people like &lt;a href="http://www.bitshifter.cc/" title="Check out the sounds of Bit Shifter">Bit Shifter&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="http://www.nullsleep.com/" title="Check out the sounds of Nullsleep">Nullsleep&lt;/a>. I’ll admit I get into it and enjoy these 8-bit masterpieces but nothing beats the originals from the games themselves, that is until they were put onto the back drop of some breakbeats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Saskrotch has put out &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://barnofhell.com/saskrotch.htm" title="Download the album">Nintendo Breakz Volume One&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, a collection of 40 classics remixed. The Megaman (Rockman) 2 remix has really got me going right now. Totally has a 1992 early hardcore feel. The Bubble Bobble remix is almost happy hardcore like with 4-4 stompyness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Coma</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/the_coma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2004 14:56:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/the_coma/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1573222739/qid=1089573630/sr=2-1/ref=sr_2_1/104-3742080-8461500" title="Check out 'The Coma' at Amazon">&lt;img alt="The Coma" src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/the-coma.jpg" width="150" height="236" border="0" class="image-right" />&lt;/a>Just read Alex Garland’s &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1573222739/qid=1089573630/sr=2-1/ref=sr_2_1/104-3742080-8461500" title="Check out 'The Coma' at Amazon">The Coma&lt;/a>&lt;/em> which not surprisingly was an ultra quick read. The book clocks in at about 200 pages with a good amount of illustrations and double spaced text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That aside I’ll say it was still a good read. &lt;em>The Coma&lt;/em> plays almost like a dream analysis in terms of what make up our dreams, the setting, characters, and events. Garland constructed the book in much the way that dreams feel to me, the sudden change in scenery or the appearance of unfamiliar people as major characters. Upon finishing the book you realize that Garland leaves the story very open ended, much like a dream, so it’s up to you to decipher the story as you feel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Orbital’s Blue Album</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/orbital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2004 11:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/orbital/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00029KZMM/qid=1089213901/sr=2-1/ref=sr_2_1/104-3742080-8461500" title="Check out the Blue Album at Amazon">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/orbital-blue-album.jpg" alt="Orbital - Blue Albm" class="image-right" border="0" height="150" width="150" />&lt;/a>I’ve long been a fan of &lt;a href="http://www.loopz.co.uk/" title="Visit the Orbital site">Orbital&lt;/a> and after &lt;em>The Altogether&lt;/em> I was somewhat disappointed with what Orbital had been putting out. When I heard that their next album would be their last I was hoping that they could redeem themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Blue Album&lt;/em> is definitely a good farewell as it touches upon the progression of their sound over the years. Tracks such as &lt;em>One Perfect Sunrise&lt;/em> and &lt;em>You Lot&lt;/em> are just pure Orbital of old but with a bit of an updated feel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epicenter Design Strategies</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/epicenter_desig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2004 13:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/07/epicenter_desig/</guid><description>&lt;p>The guys over at 37Signals always seem to come up with some good work. Their latest topic is about implementing &lt;a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/archives/000737.php" title="Learn more about Epicenter Design">&lt;em>Epicenter Design&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. Which they describe as:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote cite="http://www.37signals.com/svn/archives/000737.php">
 &lt;p>
 Epicenter design involves focusing in on the true essence of the page (the â€œepicenterâ€) and then building outwards.
 &lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Many times I feel that as designers we lose sight of the main goal of a particular page. We get so wrapped up in creating the right color scheme or layout that the true purpose of the page is lost. The &lt;em>Epicenter Design&lt;/em> approach revolves around maintaining the goal of a page during the design process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Consuming: Blogs put to good use</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/all_consuming_b/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2004 19:50:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/all_consuming_b/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years ago I was telling people how I felt that in the future there would be aggregator services which would search the web’s blogs and analyze them for topics such as movies, music, or books. I saw this as a way to get real reviews from regular people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think we’re getting closer to that with a service I came across today known as &lt;a href="http://www.allconsuming.net/">All Consuming&lt;/a>. I had come across this site from looking at referrers to my site. All Consuming searches through blogs for entries which have links to Amazon, Barnes and Noble, and so forth. These links are what bring the entry into context about a particular book. The web site then aggregates blog entries from tons of sites and you can now look up a particular book and see what people are saying about it on their blogs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wiki Wisdom</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/wiki_wisdom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2004 11:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/wiki_wisdom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spend a lot of time reading and browsing through lots of information on a daily basis and often feel that much of this information is lost due to management and organizational issues. Bookmarks don’t provide the necessary capabilities to really organize information. A lot of times I feel like I want to catalog everything I know so that I can easily refer back to it for a refresher. Unfortunately as of now my best cataloging tool is google. I’ll punch in bits of what I remember in hopes of finding some obscure information. That kind of strategy wastes a lot of time and is not an absolute guarantee. This got me to thinking about a searchable archive of my own knowledge.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MyNeu: Things have only gotten worse</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/myneu_things_ha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2004 12:26:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/myneu_things_ha/</guid><description>&lt;p>A year ago I wrote a &lt;a href="http://bryanhaggerty.com/portfolio/myneu/" title="View information about the project">paper&lt;/a> on improving the usability of Northeastern University’s student portal known as MyNeu. I sent this paper to the people in charge of MyNeu in hopes that they would hear the message from the people and maybe even implement some of the suggestions which I had made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately I can only assume my paper fell on deaf ears as since the time of that writing MyNeu has only become worse. I feel it is my duty to provide an addendum to my paper because of the latest changes which have been made on MyNeu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If I Help Won’t It Cost Less?</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/if_i_help_wont/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2004 13:34:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/if_i_help_wont/</guid><description>&lt;p>The guys from 37Signals have an interesting &lt;a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/archives/000717.php" title="See the entry in it's full glory">post&lt;/a> on their blog &lt;a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/" title="Visit their blog">Signal vs. Noise&lt;/a> about hourly rates for development work. It is obviously mostly in jest but it says a lot about the way developers feel about clients getting their hands in the nitty gritty of development. For wow factor I’ve listed the rates below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>$150/hr Standard Rate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$200/hr if you want it NOW&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$250/hr if you want to watch over my shoulder while I work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$300/hr if you want to help&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$400/hr if you worked on it first&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The most interesting aspect of this is the rate for &lt;em>if you worked on it first&lt;/em>. I totally understand why it is the most expensive because many clients always feel that since they have already done some work on it they feel that it will be done quicker and that for the developer it will be easy. I saw this all too often when I worked with clients who were somewhat tech savvy. They would run a huge document through Microsoft Office’s &lt;em>Save as HTML&lt;/em> feature and think they were doing us a favor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ugoff or Mugatu</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/ugoff_or_mugatu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2004 15:34:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/ugoff_or_mugatu/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Ugoff and Mugatu" src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/ugoff-mugatu.jpg" width="200" height="112" border="0" class="image-right" />Lately there has been a big buzz over the new ad campaigns from Burger King. From what I’ve read their new ad agency is looking to tap into the professional 20-something market. While I don’t eat a lot of fast food I will say I like how they are diversifying themselves from the likes of McDonalds and Wendy’s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But back on topic, BK’s latest ad spot features a very Mugatu (Will Ferrell in &lt;em>Zoolander&lt;/em>) like character, even down to the personality and body language. While I do find this a bit of a rip off I somewhat enjoyed the spot. The character in this case is named &lt;a href="http://www.ugoff.com" title="Check out Ugoff's site">Ugoff&lt;/a> and he features his own site much like the subservient chicken did.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ohayou gozaimasu</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/ohayou_gozaimasu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2004 09:27:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/ohayou_gozaimasu/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.japander.com/japander/schwarz.htm" title="See Arnold in all his Japanese glory">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/japander.jpg" width="150" height="116" border="0" alt="Arnold eating cup-0-noodles" class="image-right" />&lt;/a>The Japanese love using Hollywood actors in their commercials much like we do in the states as well but the Japanese always make hilariously fun ads. Over the years I’ve come across a few links online which feature some of these ads but today I found the ultimate resource. &lt;a href="http://www.japander.com" title="Visit Japander.com">Japander.com&lt;/a> has a huge collection of ads in quicktime format.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Airport Express</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/airport_express/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2004 18:56:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/airport_express/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/">&lt;img alt="Apple's Airport Express" src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/airport-express.jpg" width="150" height="127" border="0" title="Get all the specs on Airport Express from Apple" class="image-right" />&lt;/a>Just hours after I posted the entry about the &lt;a href="http://www.sonos.com/">Sonos System&lt;/a> Apple releases &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/">Airport Express&lt;/a>. The unit is basically an access point but Apple added some really nice features to it. The one that is in reference to the Sonos system is the audio out jack to a stereo. Plug in the unit next to a stereo and plug the line out into the stereo’s line in. Now in itunes you have the ability to stream music to that access point which in turn plays on the stereo via a feature Apple has dubbed &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/airtunes.html">AirTunes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sonos Digital Music System</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/sonos_digital_m/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2004 11:33:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/sonos_digital_m/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sonos.com/" title="Check out the Sonos system">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/sonos-digital-music-system.jpg" alt="The Sonos Digital Music System" class="image-right" border="0" height="79" width="150" />&lt;/a>If I lived in a large home this would be the first thing I put in it. I am constantly listening to music where ever I am and having the ability to have your entire library of music throughout your house is just unbeatable. I don’t live in a big house and as of right now the system is only available for pre-order at $1200.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Defensive Design for the Web</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/defensive_desig/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2004 16:26:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/defensive_desig/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/073571410X/qid=1086381686/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_xs_ap_i1_xgl14/102-5906890-8409700?v=glance&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;n=507846" title="Check out 'Defensive Design for the Web' at Amazon">&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/defensive-design-book.jpg" alt="Defensive Design for the Web" class="image-right" border="0" height="195" width="150" />&lt;/a>I recently picked up &lt;a href="http://www.37signals.com" title="Visit 37Signals web site">37signals&lt;/a> new book &lt;em>Defensive Design for the Web&lt;/em>. The book offers some good insight into some of the more basic usability design issues on the web and while it is a quick read I wouldn’t recommend it to the more advanced designers. If you’re new to web design or finally realizing that there is more to creating web pages than just html this book is probably a good read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Grand Don’t Come for Free</title><link>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/a_grand_dont_co/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2004 22:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/2004/06/a_grand_dont_co/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://bryanhaggerty.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/legacy/the-streets-a-grand.jpg" alt="The Streets: A Grand Don't Come for Free" class="image-right" border="0" height="150" width="150" />I recently picked up the new Streets album and decided I’d give everyone my take on the album. While in many ways I do think the album format is dead, &lt;em>A Grand Don’t Come for Free&lt;/em> definitely makes you think otherwise. The flowing story through tracks makes you want to listen to the album from start to finish whenever you listen. Ok well ya I don’t always listen to the entire album everytime but in theory you should.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>